hey guys I made a video about this the
other day and I kind of like the way
that I did it but several people
requested me to solve it a different way
where I repeatedly Square both sides of
the equation I thought it could be cool
to see what that looks like so let's do
it for the first step let's Square both
sides on this left hand side the square
and the square root will cancel each
other out and on the right hand side I
don't really want to do 32 squar but we
can change this 32 into 2 to 5th and now
to do 2 the 5th squar we just multiply
the 5 * the 2 to get 2 10 and next we
Square both sides of the equation on
this side the square will go both to the
numerator and to the denominator it's
going to look like this and in the
denominator the square and the square
root will cancel each other out and on
the right hand side we can multiply
these exponents to give us 2 to the 20
and then once again we're going to
square both sides of the equation this
squared can distribute to this term this
term and this term it'll look like this
and then x^2 s is X to 4th this guy's
good and on the very bottom this square
root and this Square will cancel each
other out and then on the right hand
side we're going to multiply these
exponents again to give us 2 to 40th and
next step we're going to square both
sides of the equation on the left hand
side this Square will distribute to all
four of these terms it's going to look
something like this this x 4th squar
will become X to 8th the x^2 SAR is
going to become X to 4th this will be X2
and on the very bottom the square root
and a square will cancel each other out
and on the right hand side this 40 will
multiply by the two to give us 2 to the
80th power and now let's clean up this
left hand side let's focus down here x^2
/ X will simplify to just X and then X
4th / X will simplify to X cubed and
then x 8 / X Cub we can just subtract 8
- 3 to give us X 5th and now we have X
5th = 2 8th we can take the fifth root
of both sides on the left hand side we
just have X and on the right hand side
we can do this 80 / 5 to give us 2 to
the 16 and 2 the 16th power is equal to
65,536 and that's the answer to our
question we can put a box around it if
you want to see the first video I have a
link in the description how exciting